Francisco J. Alvarado

- frjalv@gmail.com
- frankk.me
- (281) 865-4163
- PO Box 211594 Dallas, TX
- Download PDF of Resume

Objective

Have an updated resume.

Background

I joined Citi in July 2013 as a CATE Rotation Analyst and I have a great interest in software development. I greaduated from The University of Texas at Austin in May 2013 and I specialied in software engineering. I was involved in a number of startups around Austin and I learned how to develop not just for the consumer but also for the business. I look forward to become a Citi Developer and I'm sure with the right rotation I can learn the skills to become a great developer. During my first rotation in CATE I was placed on the Contact Center Team and has been great experience to learn about Voice systems and how Citi is structured and operates.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin-Austin, TX

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering (B.S.E.E.) May 2013

Proficiency

I have been writing code, running servers, and experimenting with new software since 2008. By the end of college most of code I have written has been in Java, Ruby, Javascript and Bash.

Experience

Citi - Irving, TX

CitiNetworks Contact Center Analyst - July 2013 to Present

- Administrated and upgraded team's WIKI page. Created a bash script to transfer WIKI page to its own Linux Box, made it self
 upgradable, and automated it's backup system.
- Worked with SMEs and vendors to update the information on the Product Pages.
- Make design templates by creating WIKI templates for common designs so the important information can be reused thus making the design process for future designs faster.
- Worked with GVO and CATE SMEs to create a capacity pipeline tool to keep track of upcoming Contact Center voice
 applications, the resources they will consume, and to plan ahead for the purchases of extra licenses and DC pieces.
- · Redesigned the Contact Center's Bandwidth Analysis tool so project estimated bandwidth can be calculated faster and more

Servuss.com - Austin, TX

Founder/Software Engineer - December 2011 to May 2013

- Developed web applications for the servuss.com as lead designer and lead engineer building on Ruby on Rails
- Participated in the Development planning of the website
- Optimized the databases for the site to make sure they performed quickly and efficiently.
- Met with multiple Austin Entrepreneurs

Magellan Education - Austin, TX

Software Engineering Intern - January 2013 to May 2013

- Designed the "Project Hosting System" architecture
- Working on the course matching algorithm and the implementation
- Working on various aspects of the user interface.
- Various other activities involved with startups (Investor presentations, marketing, brainstorming ideas for the site, etc.)

BigBinary - Miami, FL

Collaborator - December 2012 - May 2013

- Translated documentation on the Nimbleshop GitHub
- Helped fixed various bugs

Omar's Truck Sale - Houston, TX

Web Developer - December 2012 - Present

- Creating website that links Craiglist ads to main site
- Coming soon...

Summer Intern - Summer 2011

- Troubleshot technical problems around the office.
- Provided technical support for hardware, software and network issues related to the company
- Organized and filed paperwork.

The University of Texas at Austin-Austin, TX

Compute Technician - October 2012 to Present

- Installing hardware and software systems
- Maintaining or repairing equipment
- Troubleshooting a variety of computer issues
- Setting up computer security measures
- Configure Computer Networks
- Offering technical support on-site or via phone or email

Technical Skills

Languages and Frameworks

- Ruby on Rails
- Ruby
- Java
- C
- C++

Platforms

- Mac OS X
- Microsoft Windows
- Linux (Ubuntu)

Software and Technologies

- Git
- Eclipse
- Xcode
- Microsoft Visual Studio
- Matlab

Related Courses

- Electrical Engineering Software Engineering Design, Computer Architecture, Software Testing, Algorithms, Software Engineering, Probability and Random Process, Circuit Theory. Linear Systems and Signals, Data Structures, Digital Logic Design
- Mathematics Scientific Computation in Number Analysis, Discrete Mathematics, Matrices and Matrix Calculations. Linear Algebra
- Business Accounting. Organizational Behavior and Administration, Interdisciplinary Entrepreneurship